A Guide to the Papers of Charles White, 1785-1956
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
A Guide to the Papers of Charles White, 1785-1956
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1983-41
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Charles White Papers were given as a gift to Virginia State University.
Biographical/Historical Information
Mr. Charles White is a native of Buckingham County, Virginia. He has devoted much time and effort to document the history of African-Americans in the county of Buckingham.
His research resulted in the publication of The Hidden and Forgotten. Mr. White is a retired vocational education teacher and a graduate of Virginia State University.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of materials collected by Mr. Charles White while he was engaged in writing A History of Blacks in Buckingham County, Va. There are copies of wills, letters, and news clippings. Also, included are original copies of the official journal of the Virginia Baptist Convention: The Expected.
The Expected contains material documenting the Virginia Baptist State Convention. Subjects covered include the women's museum department, the role of church and society, information about different chuches, Virginia Union University and sketches of different minutes in the convention.
Series Description
Series I. Reserach Materials Copies of documents collected by Mr. White to support his research.
Series II. Printed A. The Expected, The official organ of the Virginia Baptist Convention.
Contents List
- Research Materials
  - Correspondence (copy,letter) 1892 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Correpondence (copy) ca.1898 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Correspondence (copies) 1930-1931 (Box-folder 1:3)
    letters for pensions of blacks who served the Confederates
  - Buckingham Co. Va. Church Records-copy 1852-1887 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Teachers Monthly report, The Alexnader School- Buckingham County,Virginia 1869 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - List of Blacks killed in W.W II from Buckingham Co. Va (Box-folder 1:6)
  - General Research material about blacks in Buckingham (Box-folder 1:7)
  - General Research Materials (copies) (Box-folder 1:8)
- Printed
  - The Life and Culture of Blacks in Charlotte County, Virginia 1776-1825 1976 (Volume 2)
  - The Journal of Buckingham History. Number 1 summer 1977
  - The Expected, Vol.13 Number 2 Feb. 1943 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol.13 4 Apr. 1943 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Volume 13. Number 8 Aug. 1943 (Othertype 2)
  - The Expected, Volume 14. 4 Apr. 1944 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Volume 14. 10 Oct. 1944 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 15. 10 Oct. 1945 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 15. 11 Nov. 1945 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol. 16. 3 March 1946 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 16. 5 May 1946 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 16. 8 Aug. 1946 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 16. 10 Oct. 1946 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 16. 11 Nov. 1946 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol. 16. 12 Dec. 1946 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 17. 2 Feb. 1947 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 17. 3 Mar (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 17. 7 Aug. (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 18. 1 Jan 1948 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 18. 2 and 3 Feb & March (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 18. 6 June 1948 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 19. 7 July 1949 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 19. 11 Nov. 1949 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 20. 2 Feb. 1950 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 20. 11 Nov. 1950 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 21. 4 Apr. 1951 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 26. 8 Aug. 1954 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 26. 11 Nov. 1954 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 26. 12 1954 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 27. 1 Jan. 1955 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 27. 2 Feb. 1955 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 27. 7 July 1955 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 28. 4 April 1956 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 28. 5 May (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 28. 7 July (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 28. 9 Sept. (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 29. 1 Jan. 1957 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 29. 12 Dec. 1957 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 29. 2 Feb (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 30. 3 March 1958 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 30. 4 April (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 30. 5 May (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 32. 2 Feb. 1960 (Volume 2)
  - The Expected, Vol 37. 5 May 1965 (Volume 2)